Valentin EKEU TIEMENI

Green Card holder - No Sponsorship required

Hard worker; Natural problem solver; Analytical thinker with strong interpersonal skills; Calm under pressure.



Landover, Maryland 20785

6

+1 (240) 441-7066

 \sim

ektiva2013@gmail.com

Summary

I am a Software Engineer with experience building multi-tiered applications, created full-stack .NET Application with C#, Angular, MVC, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. In addition, I have an in-depth understanding of Object-Oriented Programming, Agile development methodology, analysis, designs and SOLID principle. I'm a really motivated person and able to learn new technologies or concepts very fast. I'm capable of handling multiple tasks and I have strong customer service skills

Professional Experience	
February 2020 - Present	Software Engineer Regency Management Services, LLC – Brandywine, MD - Working in Agile environment with a team to build an online system to manage multiples furniture store.
October 2019 – January 2020	Software Engineer Revature – Reston, MD - Working with a team to build multi-tiered applications, created full-stack .NET Application with C#, Angular, MVC, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
October 2017 – June 2019	 Production Supervisor Walmart – Washington Blvd, Arbutus, MD Manage production team and Develop best practices, routines and innovative solutions to improve production rates and quality of output.
March 2014 – September 2017	 Metrology/Industrial Engineer Polytechnics Industrial Services & Engineering - Limbe, Cameroo Responsible of metrology and innovation department and supervision of a high performing team that is capable of analyzing, troubleshooting, and repairing broken equipment, as well as performing preventive maintenance tasks.
January 2013 - February 2014	Software Engineer AMLA – Yaounde, Cameroon
	 Analysis, Design and Implementation of a Gauging and Tank-Strapping Software (using Java & SQL) based on a volumetric approach and the information System of the Station, using scientific analysis and mathematical models.
July - September 2012	Engineering Internship SELUNG Engineering – Douala, Cameroon
	 Design and Implementation of a database (using SQL+ACCESS) for the management of materials, tools, and manufactured products at SELUNG; Design and implementation of service & maintenance plans for SELUNG's machine tools.
October 2007 - July 2010	Assistant Technician SELUNG Engineering – Douala, Cameroon
	- Data base management, word processing, complete forms in accordance with company procedures
Education	
July 2019 - September 2019	Bootcamp / Software Engineering Revature - Reston, Virginia
Content	Project base Bootcamp where we created full stack web application using .Net and Angular curriculum, including C#, SQL, ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Angular 6, Azure DevOps, Docker, Algorithm and Data Structure
September 2010 - July 2013 Majors / Professional Training Modules	Master Degree / Design Engineering National Advanced School of Engineering, Yaounde
	Engineering and Production Management; Design and Development of New Products and Production Systems Quality; Information System (Databases, Networking, Programming); Operational Research, Human Resource Management and Ergonomics, Health, Safety and Environment
September 2004 – July 2008 Majors	Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics (2008) University of Yaounde 1 Numerical Analysis, Game Theory, Descriptive Statistics and Probability; Operational Research, Scientific Computing and Data Analysis, Decisional Statistic, Optimisation.
Skills and Abilities	
Technical Skills	 Web Technologies: ASP.NET Web API, .NET MVC, Web Services, HTML5, AJAX & JQuery, CSS, Angula Programming Language: JavaScript, Java, C#, Python, VB/VBA, C+, Matlab, PHP. Database & Storage: SQLite, SQL, SQL Server, MySQL, NoSQL, ACCESS, AWS, Microsoft Azure SQL Database. Devops: Kubernetes, Postman, Docker, Git, Azure DevOps, SonarCloud, Azure. Amazon Web Services: IAM, AWS EC2, AWS EBS, AWS AMI, AWS VPC, AWS SQS. Strong proficiency with Microsoft Office applications and statistical tools (Excel, Word, Minitab, PowerPoint Lean Six Sigma green belt level capability with strong Knowledge in application of DMAIC, DFSS and Lean Tools. Solid understanding of Object Oriented Programming, SOLID principle, business and IT processes.
Communication & interpersonal Skills	 Solid three standing of Object Oriented Programming, SOLID principle, Business and 11 processes. Excellent team-working and Leadership abilities. Good integration in the workplace. Eager, ambitious, and adaptable to change Excellent attention to detail and strong organizational and time management abilities